Finding Aid for College of Engineering (University of Michigan) records 1860-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Visual Materials, circa 1900-1975
  - Photographs
    - Laboratories and Equipment
      - Automotive Engineering, 1959; black and white positive prints (Box 50)
      - Miscellaneous (identified), 1967; color positive print (Box 50)
    - Mechanical Engineering, Department of
      - Graduates, 1930-1940; black and white positive prints (Box 50)
    - Observatory, Peach Mountain (Portage Lake, MI), ca., 1958; black and white positive prints (Box 50)
    - People, miscellaneous (most identified), 1967; black and white positive prints (Box 50)
    - Science and Technology, Institute of
      - Special Projects Division staff, 1987; color positive prints (Box 50)
    - Aerial and Construction Views of North Campus, circa 1955; 1964; 1988; 5 prints black and white (Box 82)
    - Alumni (see also box 83 oversized)
      - Class of 1904 Reunions, 1914-1954; undated; 25 prints black and white (Box 82)
      - Class of '42 E Plaza, 1996; 3 prints color (Box 82)
      - Classes of, 1911; 1920; 1930; 1938; 1936-1973; 4 prints black and white (Box 82)
    - Building Exteriors, 1961-1988; undated; 13 prints black and white; 3 prints color (Box 82)
    - Building Interiors, circa 1930s; 4 prints black and white (Box 82)
    - Camp Davis and Surveying Groups, 1875; 1917; undated; 5 prints black and white (Box 82)
    - Class Pictures (oversize: see box 83) (Box 82)
    - Diversity Day (includes picture of Andrew Young), 1989; 9 prints black and white (Box 82)
    - Faculty
      - Group Portraits, 1928-1930; 10 prints black and white (Box 82)
      - Individual Portraits, circa 1950s-1980s; 50 portraits in 2 folders black and white (Box 82)
    - Laboratories and Equipment, circa 1910s-1920s; 38 prints in 2 folders black and white (Box 82)
    - Laboratory and Library Scenes, circa 1920s; 17 prints in 1 binder black and white (Box 82)
    - Michigan Technic
      - Experimental Car, circa 1970; 4 prints black and white (Box 82)
      - Laboratory scenes, circa 1970s; 9 prints black and white (Box 82)
      - Student Life, circa 1970s; 30 prints black and white (Box 82)
      - Student Life, incl. Society of Women Engineers Career Fair, 1987-1988; 5 contact sheets black and white; 3 negatives number approximate (Box 82)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1970s-1980s; 4 prints color; 12 prints black and white (Box 82)
    - Miscellaneous Buildings and Faculty, circa 1850s-1930s; 114 prints 1 binder black and white (Box 82)
    - Negatives-some may match prints, circa 1910s-1920s; 28 negatives black and white 8x10 (Box 82)
    - North Campus Scenes, 1987; 17 prints black and white (Box 82)
    - Recruitment Fair, 1988; 2 prints black and white; 7 prints color (Box 82)
    - Class Pictures (oversize black and white prints)
      - "A Group of Early Engineering Graduates", circa 1860s (Box 83)
      - 1865 (Box 83)
      - 1868 (Box 83)
      - 1869 (Box 83)
      - 1870 (Box 83)
      - 1871 (Box 83)
      - 1872 (Box 83)
      - 1873 (Box 83)
      - 1874 (Box 83)
      - 1875 (Box 83)
      - 1876 (Box 83)
      - 1877 (Box 83)
      - 1878 (Box 83)
      - 1881 (Box 83)
      - 1884 (Box 83)
      - 1885 (Box 83)
      - 1886 (Box 83)
      - 1887 (Box 83)
      - 1888 (Box 83)
      - 1899 (Box 83)
      - 1916 (Box 83)
      - 1933 (Box 83)
      - 1940 (Box 83)
      - circa 1920s (Box 83)
      - Camp Davis, 1885 (Box 83)
      - Mechanical Engineering, 1895 (Box 83)
    - Engineering Arch drawing, undated (Box 83)
    - Portraits of Prominent Alumni, circa 1910s-1920s; 26 prints (Box 83)
    - Faculty group photo, circa 1960 (Box 83)
    - Graduation Composites and Class Photographs
      - undated (Box 94)
      - Randal '98 (Box 94)
      - 1869 (Box 94)
      - 1870 (Box 94)
      - 1872 (Box 94)
      - 1873 (Box 94)
      - 1874 (Box 94)
      - 1877 (Box 94)
      - 1881 (Box 94)
      - 1883 (Box 94)
      - 1885 (Box 94)
      - 1886 (Box 94)
      - 1908 (Box 94)
      - 1911 (Box 94)
      - 1914 (Box 94)
      - 1915 (Box 94)
      - 1922 (Box 94)
      - 1927 (Box 94)
      - 1928 (Box 94)
      - 1931 (Box 94)
      - 1932 (Box 94)
      - 1933 (Box 94)
      - 1934 (Box 94)
      - 1938 (Box 94)
      - 1939 (Box 94)
      - 1940 (Box 94)
      - A Group of Early Graduates (Folder 1)
        (composite includes students Peter S. Gibson, 1861; Elmore H. Wells, 1862; Abel R. Flint, 1866; Joseph W. Woods, 1861; George H. Benzenberg, 1867; James Steel, 1867; Lewis Foote, 1866; Lowell A. Goodman, 1867; Sanford F. Bennett, student 1858-1860; William Minto, 1860; Lt. Col. William M. Reed, 1861; William S. McHarg, 1868; Frank L. Kraus, 1860; Elijah Treadwell, 1869; Stillman W. Robinson, 1863; Ira S. Dunning, 1863)
      - 1868 (Folder 1)
      - 1871 (Folder 1)
      - 1875 (Folder 1)
      - 1878 (Folder 1)
      - 1887 (Folder 1)
      - 1888 (Folder 1)
      - 1895 (Folder 1)
      - Undated, [1897] (Folder 1)
      - 1904 (Folder 1)
      - 1905 (Folder 1)
      - 1906 (Folder 1)
      - 1907 (Folder 1)
      - 1909 (Folder 1)
      - 1910 (Folder 1)
      - 1912 (Folder 2)
      - 1913 (Folder 2)
      - 1916 (Folder 2)
      - 1918 (Folder 2)
      - 1920 (Folder 2)
      - 1921 (Folder 2)
      - 1923 (Folder 2)
      - 1924 (Folder 2)
      - 1925 (Folder 2)
      - 1930 (Folder 2)
      - (2), 1931 (Folder 2)
      - 1936 (Folder 2)
      - (2), 1937 (Folder 2)
  - Slides
    - North and Campus 1A-300A, 1980-1990 (Box 95)
      (includes index)
    - North Campus 1B-556B (Box 95)
    - Faculty., 1983-1988 (Box 95)
    - Faculty 1D-296D, 1983-1988 (Box 95)
      (includes Meerkov; Teorey; Mathes; Haddad; Chuang; MacAfee; Lomax; Wise; Segal; Dudersatdt; Goldberg; Clark; Cole; Pollock; Chaffin; Vest; Merte; Lady; Greabel; Herrin; Hosfo rd; VanVlock; Anderson; Howe; Caddell; Datsko; McClamroch; Jain; Naylor; Mudge; Irani; Williams; Senior; Federbush)
    - Martin Luther King, Jr. Day 1E-137E, 1990 (Box 95)
    - North Campus, 1991 (Box 95)
    - Spring Fest, 1991 (Box 95)
  - Drawings
    - One technical drawing, undated (Folder BImu C141)
    - Autographed memento of surveying class, 1889 (Folder BImu C141)
  - Videotape
    - National Closed Circuit Telecast, 1974; U-matic (Box 83)
- Scrapbooks
  - 1918 Engineers, 1918-1978 (Box 82)
  - Department of Naval Architecture and Marine Engineering Groundbreaking, 1977 (Box 82)
  - "From His Friends to W.S. Housel", 1970; 2 volumes (Box 82)
- Course Approval Forms, circa 1973-2001
  - Aerospace Engineering, 4 folders (Box 98)
  - Applied Mechanics, 3 folders (Box 98)
  - Atmospheric Oceanic Space Engineering, 4 folders (Box 98)
  - Biomedical Engineering, 2 folders (Box 98)
  - Chemical Engineering, 3 folders (Box 98)
  - Civil Engineering, 3 folders (Box 98)
  - Civil Environmental Engineering (Box 98)
  - Electrical Engineering and Computer Science (EECS) (Box 99)
    - (100-499), 3 folders (Box 99)
    - (500-999), 3 folders (Box 99)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 99)
  - Engineering, 3 folders (Box 99)
  - Environmental Engineering (Box 99)
  - Humanities (Box 99)
  - Industrial & Operations Engineering
    - (0-499), 3 folders (Box 99)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 99)
    - (500-999), 2 folders (Box 100)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 100)
  - Manufacturing, 2 folders (Box 100)
  - Materials Science & Engineering, 3 folders (Box 100)
  - Mathematics (Box 100)
  - Mechanical Engineering
    - (0-499), 2 folders (Box 100)
    - (500-990), 3 folders (Box 100)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 100)
  - Naval Architecture & Marine Engineering, 4 folders (Box 100)
  - Nuclear Engineering, 3 folders (Box 100)
  - Operations Management (Box 100)
  - School of Information SI (Electronic Commerce) (Box 100)
  - Technical Communication (Box 100)
- Degree Lists and Profiles
  - Degree Lists, 1920-1993
    - 1920-1947 (Box 101)
    - 1948-May 1967 (Box 101)
    - August 1967-December 1969 (Box 101)
    - May 1970-Decemeber, 1974 (Box 101)
      [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2049 ]
    - May 1975-December 1979 (Box 101)
      [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2054 ]
    - May 1908-Decembere, 1984 (Box 101)
      [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2059 ]
    - 1982-1983 (Box 101)
      [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2058 ]
    - 1984-1985 (Box 101)
      [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2060 ]
    - May 1985-December 1989 (Box 101)
      [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2064 ]
    - 1986-1988 (Box 101)
      [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2063 ]
    - 1988-1990 (Box 101)
      [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2065 ]
    - 1991-1993 (Box 101)
      [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2068 ]
  - Degree Profiles, 1981-1995
    - Statistical Profiles
      - Degree, 1922-1994 (Box 101)
      - Faculty, Staff & Students of Color, 1981-1992 (Box 101)
    - Surveys of Degrees, 1987-1995 (Box 101)
- Archived College of Engineering Website
  The College of Engineering Archived Website series documents the academic programs, accomplishments, resources, events, and people at the College of Engineering. Content includes important news and announcements, publications (such as newsletters and course catalogs), and information about admissions, curriculum, degree requirements, faculty, and the overall mission of the College. The website series is arranged chronologically, with captures from 2002 and 2003 stored on CD. Starting in 2010, this archived website will be captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/.
  - Website capture, May 15, 2002; 1 optical disks CDs (Box 2)
    (Original URL http://www.engin.umich.edu)
  - Website capture, June 23, 2003; 1 optical disks CDs (Box 2)
  - Archived College of Engineering home page, 2010-[ongoing]
  - Archived websites related to the College of Engineering, 2010-[ongoing]
- Committees
  The 2004 accession consists of three volumes relating to the College of Engineering's strategic plan for future years. It adds a new subseries, Strategic Planning Committee, 2004, to the Committee Records series. In addition to the general College of Engineering Strategic Plan, dated April 1, 2004, the accession includes an August 2004 report from the Strategic Planning Implementation Communication Committee and a May 2004 volume from the Strategic Planning Implementation Faculty Committee.
  - Strategic Plan, 2004
    - Strategic Plan, April 1, 2004 (Box 102)
    - Strategic Planning Implementation Communication Committee Report, August 2004 (Box 102)
    - Strategic Planning Implementation Faculty Committee Report, May 2004 (Box 102)